## David Bensoussan

# **Software Engineer**

**(**+49)176/34626472

A Paris, France

**Stuttgart**, Germany

In a few words I am a passionate of new technologies and particularly bensoussan.dev@gmail.com robotics and all its fields of application. I am currently working in Synapticon, in the Stuttgart area for 3 years, on the software for an autonomous robot. I have mainly worked on devops topics (CI/CD) but also on high level with ROS, low level using SOMANET and the development of the embedded linux. I also recently started doing Freelancing in devops topics to challenge my skills and enhance my knowledge by delivering more applications.

## **Experiences**



March 2015 - today (3 years) Full time

♦CI/CD, OS, HIGH AND LOW LEVEL SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT FOR AN AUTONOMOUS ROBOT TARGETING THE CONSUMER MARKET

• (Expert) Created and continuously improving a fully automated CI build and deployment **infrastructure** and processes for multiple projects. Developed containers to support my colleagues and their pipelines. Worked on the Architecture, Development, Test, Security and IT Services (using AWS). Writing scripts for build, deployment, maintenance and related tasks using Jenkins, Docker, Terraform, Packer, Python and Bash. Installing, configuring and maintaining Continuous Integration, **Automation and Configuration Management tools** 

- (Expert) Building and managing optimized embedded systems using
- (Good knowledge) Developing low level software on XMOS multicore chips: sensors and motor control applications
- (Knowledgeable) High level software with ROS. Localization and navigation in C++ and python

Being in a small team, I have been involved in different parts of the project at start: low level, high level, benchmarks and testing. I am working with development best practices in an agile environment.

FREELANCING

May 2018 - today

MAINTOOL

April - July 2014 Internship

DEVOPS DEVELOPER/MANAGER

Improving and creating CI/CD process, putting applications in containers, providing more robust development environments.

♥ HEART RATE SENSOR DESIGN

Electronic design of the main sensor of a connected watch strap, based on LEDs and photodiode. I also developed the software for it. It is now included in their main product.

#### Education

#### **ESIEA**

GRADUATE SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING - MASTER 2

2010 - 2015

Embedded systems major, 3 years in robotics student organization (including one year of presidency), robotics **courses and competition** organization.